You mentioned that to choose a summary metric,
你说过 要选择一个总指标
we need to think about the sensitivity and the robustness of the metric.
我们需要考虑这个指标的敏感性和稳健性
Can you explain that more?
你能讲得详细些吗？
>> Yeah, so in lesson one,
是的 在第一课中
we talked about the sensitivity of a test to a change that you care about.
我们谈到了你所关心的更改测试的敏感性
The sensitivity of a metric is kind of the same thing.
一个指标的敏感性也是类似
The idea is that you want to choose a metric that picks up changes you care
你想选择能够捕捉到你所关心的更改的指标
about but, this is the idea of robustness,
这就是稳健性的概念
is robust against changes that you don't care about.
是针对你所关心的更改的稳健性
So it doesn't move a lot when nothing interesting has happened.
因此 当不发生任何有趣的事情时 它不会发生太大改变
>> I think that makes sense, but could you give me some examples?
我认为这很好理解 但你能给出一些例子吗？
>> Sure. So
当然
on our latency example where we're looking at the load time of a video,
视频加载时间延迟示例
that's a great example of kind of classical statistics.
是典型统计数据的一个很好的示例
Do you use the mean or do you use the median?
你使用平均值还是中位数？
Or, in our case, you may use neither.
或者 在我们的例子中 你两者都不选择
And the idea is that the mean is sensitive to outliers.
因此 平均值对异常值很敏感
So, if in your data you see a lot of cases of really long load times,
因此 如果在你的数据中 你看到加载时间总是很长
maybe due to something going on in the users machine, or a bad network
这可能是因为用户机器原因或网络连接不良
connection, then you want to maybe not choose the mean, because the mean is
你想选择平均值 因为平均值
going to be pretty heavily influenced by those types of observations.
受各类观察结果的影响很大
And so that's called not being robust.
因此不能称为稳健
Now, on the other hand, you could choose the median,
另一方面 你可以选择中位数
which tends to be much more robust to that type of behavior, but if you
这对于此类行为更稳健 但如果你
only affect a fraction of your users, even if it's a fairly large fraction,
只影响你的一小部分用户 即使是很大一部分用户
like 20% with a change, you might not see the median move at all.
例如 20% 你可能都不会看到中位数有任何变化
So the median is robust.
因此 中位数是稳健的
But in this case,
但在这个例子中
you might want to actually consider using some other statistics,
你可能考虑使用其他一些统计数据
such as the 90th or the 99th percentile, and see how those change as well.
例如 90% 或 99% 看看它们是如何变化的
So they might be a better reflection of what you're actually trying to measure.
因此 它们可能很好地反应你想要测量的信息
>> Okay.
是的
So how would you actually measure the sensitivity and robustness?
那么你会如何测量敏感性和稳健性呢？
>> Well, there are two main ways and ideally, you could do both.
主要有两种方法 理想情况是你可以选择这两种情况
The first has to do with running experiments or
第一种是进行实验或
using experiments you already have.
使用你已经有的实验
So, for example, in our latency example, we could run a few simple experiments
例如 在我们的延迟示例中 我们可以实施一些简单的实验
where we say, increase the quality of the video which should,
我们可以提高视频的质量
in theory, increase the load time for users.
在理论上 我们可以增加用户加载时间
And we could see if the metrics were interested in, actually respond to that.
我们可以看看你感兴趣的指标是否对这种情况做出响应
Now the date is going to get a little fuzzier so
现在 日期有些模糊
they may not respond exactly that way we think, but we should be able to tell
因此 他们不能准确地按照我们的方式响应 但我们应该能够
if they're actually moving in a way that intuitively makes sense.
通过直觉判断他们是否真的改变了
And we can also use what were called a versus a experiments to determine if
我们也能够使用 A/A 实验确定
they're too sensitive.
它们是否太敏感
That's an experiment where you don't change anything.
在这个实验中 你不修改任何指标
You just compare people who saw the same thing to each other.
只将能看到相同信息的人们进行比较
And you see if your metrics pick up any spurious differences between the two.
看看你的指标是否显示两者之间的差别
And that's a really critical element to make sure that you're not going to be
通过这个关键元素 你可以确保
calling things significant that maybe don't really mean anything.
不会将一些实际上没有任何意义的东西认为是重要的
And then you can also look back at experiments that were run by
你可以回过头来看看
your company earlier.
你公司以前实施的实验
If you have experiments that have happened before and
如果你的实验以前被使用过
you also now have the benefit of hindsight,
你现在也受益
you may have user data about how well people liked it and how they responded.
你可能会获得关于人们有多喜欢它 如何响应的用户数据
You can certainly look and
当然你可以看看
see if those experiments move the metric you're interested in.
这些实验是否改变了你感兴趣的指标
Now, the second main category of things you can look at is
你可以查看的第二大类是
sort of a retrospective analysis of your logs.
对你记录的回顾性分析
If you don't have experiment data or if you can't run new experiments,
如果你没有实验数据 或如果你不能实施新的实验
then you can look back at changes you know you made to your site, and
回头看看你对你的网站做过的更改
see if the metrics you're interested in actually moved in conjunction with those
看看你感兴趣的这些指标是否和这些更改一同发生了
changes.
变化
Or you can just look at the history of the the metric and
或者你可以只看指标历史
see if you can find a cause for any major changes that you see.
看看你是否能够找出主要更改的原因
That can help you get some good intuition about what's going on.
这能帮助你获得一些关于当前形势的直觉